Raymond Muller | Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, United States | (925)-639-7520 | mullerr@purdue.edu

Summary

Graduate Computer Science student with a computer vision, machine learning, and security background. I have interned at several government institutions working on various computer-related applications spanning computer vision, network security, software engineering, and web development. I have developed 3 major open-source projects, including one used by the Mount Diablo Unified School district. I am currently working on academic research on autonomous systems and perception. I am also skilled in multiple different martial arts, have an open water diving certification, and I am a former Western States Chess Champion.

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant – Purdue University

Aug 2022 — Present

Conducting research as part of the the PurSec Lab under Dr. Berkay Celik.

Computational Engineering Student Intern — Lawrence Livermore Ntnl Labs — Summers 2019 — Prsnt Over the course of nearly 4 years I have worked on various aspects of Ground Penetrating Radar Systems, including implementing object detection systems, creating UIs through full stack development, and dockerization of certain

applications.

Graduate Teaching Assistant — Purdue University

Aug 2020 — August

2022

Working with instructors and teams of 3-4 Teaching Assistants to lead

instructional labs.

Coach — Apex Movement Norcal

Aug 2018 — Aug 2020

Main responsibilities included teaching parkour to lower level youth and adult classes, monitoring open gym, and providing assistance to the front desk.

Student Intern — CCC Department of Information Technology

Oct 2018 — May 2019

Worked on web and software development for Contra Costa County Tax Collector's Office.

Teaching Assistant — California State University East Bay

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

NSF-Technology Pathways TA under Dr. Jiaofei Zhong for Summer Quarter 2018. Work involved creating homework, slides, presentation materials, and assignments for students in the CS200 course using Python, with a Health-Sciences theme.

Education

Purdue Unive	ersity –	PhD, C	omput	er Science	<u> </u>				2020 -	- 2024
						_				

Working in computer vision and security research under Dr. Berkay Celik.

California State University - East Bay — MS, Computer Science 2019 - 2020 Graduated with Master's of Science in Computer Science with a 3.97 GPA.

California State University - East Bay — BS, Computer Science 2017 - 2018
Graduated Summa Cum Laude in December 2018.

Publications

- DRIVETRUTH: Automated Autonomous Driving Dataset Generation for Security Applications (AutoSec 2022)
- Physical Hijacking Attacks against Object Trackers (ACM CCS 2022)

Talks / Lectures

- Guest Lecturer at Purdue, CS 592 IoT/CPS, "Machine Learning for Perception and Decision Making (April 4th 2022)
- Lightning Talk at Future Automotive Research Datasets: Challenges and Opportunities, invited by David Balenson at USC, "Automated Autonomous Driving Dataset Generation for Security Applications" (November 18th 2022)

Certifications

- Certificate of Robotics Engineering and Programming with Vex (Villanova University)
- First Degree Black Belt in Tae Kwon Do (World Taekwondo Fededration)
- Open Water Diving Certification (SDI)

Skills

```
Computer Vision • Python • Computer Javascript • Robotics • Penetration Testing • Leadership • Web Development • Machine Learning • Research • C++
```

Honors and Awards

• General Motors Security AutoDriving Security Award (April 24, 2022)

- Western States Chess Champion.
- Junior Olympic Swimmer